Food stamps are being cut, but here's how we're going to feed our communities anyway.
Three easy steps. This is what I've learned after feeding over 600 people in six months
with my mutual aid group, Mutual Rise. Step one, start a nonprofit or start collaborating with one.
This is a very important distinction. The mission for the nonprofit must be to freely feed your
neighbors who are experiencing food insecurity. Step two, use the nonprofit to contact food
businesses so you can start getting food donations. You can do this in person, via email, or on the
phone. I'm talking restaurants, grocery stores, bakeries, food trucks, convenience stores, local
farms, anywhere that sells food. Why does this work? Because all of these businesses produce some level
of food waste or food overflow. This just means perfectly good food that does not get eaten or
sold for whatever reason. So instead of the businesses throwing the food away and experiencing
that loss, you can provide them your nonprofit EIN and they can donate the food to you and get a tax
write-off. It's a win-win situation. Some businesses don't even care about the tax write-off. They just
want to get the wasted food off of their hands so they can get in new product and go through the entire
supply chain again of selling. Step three, once you have an agreement, pick up the food, inspect the
quality, and start freely distributing it to the families and individuals in your community who
really need it right now. It really is that straightforward. Always remember, we live in a
world full of abundance and scarcity is what? Manufactured. We are not powerless. Go out, empower yourself
and your community and get the food that's available right now. No one needs to go hungry and all food
should be free. So good luck. Get out there and let me know if you have any questions. Bye.